<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.gorangligorin.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.gorangligorin.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-11-22T11:10:40+00:00</updated><id>https://www.gorangligorin.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Goran Gligorin</title><subtitle>Goran Gligorin's little piece of the Internet</subtitle><author><name>Goran Gligorin</name><email>goran@gligorin.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Samsung Galaxy S2</title><link href="https://www.gorangligorin.com/blog/samsung-galaxy-s2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Samsung Galaxy S2" /><published>2011-07-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.gorangligorin.com/blog/samsung-galaxy-s2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.gorangligorin.com/blog/samsung-galaxy-s2">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/sgs2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Samsung Galaxy S2&quot; title=&quot;Samsung Galaxy S2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I finally got myself a decent phone. I’m not saying my old Nokia 5800 was that bad. Well actually it was a slow, single touch device with very little useful apps. It didn’t even have proper threaded messaging for crying out loud. So that’s why I’ve gone and gotten myself a brand new Samsung Galaxy S2, code name I9100 for all you tech geeks out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m really happy with for now, although I’ve still got a lot of apps to find and customize the hell out of it. And that’s actually what I’m doing now. I found this WordPress app and I’m taking it for a test drive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I guess I’m done for now.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Goran Gligorin</name><email>goran@gligorin.com</email></author><category term="tech" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Exams? Done!</title><link href="https://www.gorangligorin.com/blog/exams-done" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Exams? Done!" /><published>2011-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.gorangligorin.com/blog/exams-done</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.gorangligorin.com/blog/exams-done">&lt;p&gt;It’s been quite a while since my last post. I’ve been busy. Not a good excuse, but it’s all I’ve got. I had 2 exams left at the end of September and I’m glad to say their finally behind me. It’s quite an achievement for me and it’s implications are only now beginning to dawn on me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/exams-done.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;No more exams.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a mind boggling thought. I can not believe that from now on I can actually learn what I want to. Don’t get me wrong. I definitely picked the right school to go to and the courses themselves or rather the ideas for them were mostly OK. The problems lay in the execution of these courses. Some went too deep yet others went to wide. Professors didn’t seem to get were the sweet spot is. The worst thing about it was, that they didn’t seem to try or even care and find it. This left us students frustrated which is not a way to go if you want to motivate young minds. I must admit that these last 2 exams took everything I’ve got to get through. But I did it and I’m really proud of myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what does this mean? It means I’ve only got one thing left to reach the end of the path that is formal education - diploma. On Friday I’m going to hand in all the forms and papers to make it formal. If you’re interested my thesis is going to be about &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Recommender_system&quot; title=&quot;Recommender Systems&quot;&gt;recommender systems&lt;/a&gt;. I’m still waiting on a formal title, but that’s my mentor’s job. I’m actually really looking forward to getting to work. Should be fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just to keep this a wholesome post let add that this is the only part (finish school) of my &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2011-new-years-resolution&quot; title=&quot;2011 New Year's Resolution&quot;&gt;New Year’s resolution&lt;/a&gt; I’ve been working on. With exams behind me it now makes it a lot easier to focus on other goals. My parents were kind enough to help me through the past few months financially, but getting a job is now quite high on my priority list. I’ll also start working out as it started to warm up outside. Socializing is probably the last on my list, but I’ve got to make sacrifices somewhere, don’t I?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Goran Gligorin</name><email>goran@gligorin.com</email></author><category term="personal" /><summary type="html">It’s been quite a while since my last post. I’ve been busy. Not a good excuse, but it’s all I’ve got. I had 2 exams left at the end of September and I’m glad to say their finally behind me. It’s quite an achievement for me and it’s implications are only now beginning to dawn on me.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2011 New Years Resolution</title><link href="https://www.gorangligorin.com/blog/2011-new-years-resolution" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2011 New Years Resolution" /><published>2011-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.gorangligorin.com/blog/2011-new-years-resolution</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.gorangligorin.com/blog/2011-new-years-resolution">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/new-years-resolutions-2011.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet another New Year’s resolution post, you might say. Well, it is. This post is meant for me to share with you my plans for this year. But more importantly its purpose is to put these plans on black and white, so they don’t escape my mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let start with what I accomplished over this past year. As I didn’t yet have a blog back then, I posted this on Facebook:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;2010 New Year’s resolutions? Got those. Maybe too much of them, but the biggest ones: Finish school (due date January 2011), finish at least four small and one medium/big project and go on one bigger trip (probably Australia). Other ones are of secondary nature or still under consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately most of these fell through. Why, you ask. Let’s see - Australia didn’t work out because I didn’t have enough money. And school just got dragged out a bit. I did manage to publish at least one small project - &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/mvcopenid-open-source-openid-starter-kit-for-asp-net-mvc&quot; title=&quot;MvcOpenID - Open Source OpenID Starter Kit for ASP.NET MVC&quot;&gt;MvcOpenID&lt;/a&gt;. And this blog can be another one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it’s 2011 now, so let’s focus on that. A few goals will closely resemble last year ones. As I don’t have that much school to worry about I’m also adding some new ones. And here, in order of order of importance, they are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish school&lt;/strong&gt; - With some luck I’ll finish it by June, but the end of September is the ultimate goal to get my diploma.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get a job&lt;/strong&gt; - I want to stay in Ljubljana, but for that I need a job to pay the rent. This goal is a bit on the urgent side, as I need the job by the end of this month. Wish me luck.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4 web projects&lt;/strong&gt; - I won’t specify sizes this year, but I hope at least one of these 4 will grow into something bigger. This is the only real all-year-long goal and as I want to make a career with web projects, I’m setting a goal at least $300 a month from these projects.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Travel to USA&lt;/strong&gt; - This is 2011’s big trip plan. Me and my mates are planning to go to the west coast of USA. You know - LA, San Francisco, Las Vegas, maybe a bit of Mexico. The trip should take place at the end of summer or in the start of fall. After all of us get our diplomas. This is another reason I need a job.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loose weight and get fit&lt;/strong&gt; - This is a topic I’ve written about before. I’ll give it my all this year. And because they say goals work better if your specific - I want to have 70kg and a six pack before summer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Socialize more&lt;/strong&gt; - I’ve been neglecting my social life a bit over the past year as I focused my attention on school and career, but I hope to find time and get out a bit more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There you go. Seems a lot to do, eh? Well it probably is. But I’ll give it my best shot. I’ve read an interesting &lt;a href=&quot;https://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748703478704574612052322122442.html#articleTabs%3Darticle&quot; title=&quot;Blame It On the Brain&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; about New Year’s resolutions and it gave me an idea. I’ll have some kind of a goal management system that will keep me on track and enable me to further specify my goals. I’ll of course write about these goals and how they’re coming along right here, on my blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well that’s that. Wish me luck and if you have any New Year’s resolutions yourself, share them in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Goran Gligorin</name><email>goran@gligorin.com</email></author><category term="goals" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New (Dream) Machine (Part 1)</title><link href="https://www.gorangligorin.com/blog/new-dream-machine-part-1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New (Dream) Machine (Part 1)" /><published>2010-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.gorangligorin.com/blog/new-dream-machine-part-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.gorangligorin.com/blog/new-dream-machine-part-1">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/dream-machine.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking about getting myself a new computer for a while now. For the past 3 years I’ve owned an Acer 5920G laptop which is slowly dying on me. But increasingly frequent random crashes, as annoying as they are, are not the biggest problem. With me being (at least recently) a web developer and my style of programming I burn through those 2 gigs of RAM in an instant. I thought about replacing them with 4 gigs, but that would just fix the problem for a few months. So I decided to replace my laptop, that gets a 4.7 rating in Windows 7, with a brand new desktop computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose a desktop computer over a new laptop because of a few simple reasons. First, I’ll still have this laptop if I need one. I don’t really need my primary machine to be portable and with tools like DropBox I can always have the important stuff with me. The second reason is a bit subjective. With a laptop I don’t really feel that I have enough control over the hardware. Yes, you can change the optical unit, add more memory, swap the hard drive, but you can’t really change the important stuff like the CPU or the graphics card. And don’t event get me started with how you can change a thing about the cooling. And you can do all of these things with a desktop computer, hence my choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found quite a nice pre-built computer on an Austrian online shop, but could not order because I don’t live in Austria. So I started reading reviews and test and other whatnots about the hardware out there. I was at it for almost the whole per-Christmas week. But I did it. So let me present you with a list of the components I chose:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Asus Sabertooth X58&lt;/strong&gt; - a motherboard with a bit of futuristic stuff like USB3 and SATA3, 2 PCI-e slots and quite a few good reviews.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intel i7-950&lt;/strong&gt; - a snappy 3.06GHz processor with 4 cores.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corsair XMS3 6GB Triple Channel DDR3 Memory Kit (CMX6GX3M3A1333C9)&lt;/strong&gt; - 3 times more memory then my laptop should suffice for now. The motherboard will still have 3 empty slots so an upgrade to 12 or 18 GB won’t be a problem in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sapphire 5770HD 1GB GDDR5&lt;/strong&gt; - the graphics card that should play all the modern games and full HD 1080p videos on my 24” LCD.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Samsung Spinpoint F3 1TB&lt;/strong&gt; - a hard drive that is big enough to hold all of my data.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Samsung SH-S223C&lt;/strong&gt; - a cheap DVD burner just so I have an optical unit.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LC-Power LC6650GP3 V2.3 GREEN POWER&lt;/strong&gt; - a 650W power supply should be enough to power all of components above.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Antec SLK3700&lt;/strong&gt; - an older Antec case to fit in all the parts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you know anything about computer hardware (and I think you do if you’re still reading), you see that this will be quite a powerful piece of machinery. And that’s what I wanted. I finally have a computer I always wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the orders are in and I hope to get all the parts in first week of 2011. I’ll post some pictures of the components themselves as they come in and then the whole rig. So stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Goran Gligorin</name><email>goran@gligorin.com</email></author><category term="tech" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Programming or Creating - Which Is My Passion?</title><link href="https://www.gorangligorin.com/blog/programming-or-creating-which-is-my-passion" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Programming or Creating - Which Is My Passion?" /><published>2010-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.gorangligorin.com/blog/programming-or-creating-which-is-my-passion</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.gorangligorin.com/blog/programming-or-creating-which-is-my-passion">&lt;p&gt;I found a very interesting question on Programmers (a Stack Exchange Q&amp;amp;A site):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Is programming your passion or is creating your passion?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This made me think. Here’s my answer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;For me, &lt;strong&gt;creating and programming/coding exchange the roles of passion and medium&lt;/strong&gt;.
Let me elaborate that a bit. I have 2 things that get me going - &lt;strong&gt;an idea&lt;/strong&gt; for a project or &lt;strong&gt;a puzzle&lt;/strong&gt;.
Puzzles are pure coding challenges for me and while I usually feel intrigued by them, most of the time I get a guilty feeling of procrastination. I’m talking here about coding puzzle like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pex4fun.com/&quot; title=&quot;Pex4Fun&quot;&gt;Pex4Fun&lt;/a&gt; where the only thing you get from solving a puzzle is self-confirmation.
If I start with an idea coding is my medium to release the creative energy that has built up inside of me while playing around with the idea in my head. I’m not one of those programmers who just write code to create and say they’re done when the application has all the functionality they envisioned. No, I also want to make my code pretty, clean with lots of cleverness in it. I hate spaghetti code and I love refactoring. I also love code architecture and patterns. This is where creativity becomes a medium to my coding passion. This is also where puzzles come in. As I said, I love solving puzzles and this time I don’t feel like I’m procrastinating. When I feel happy about the code I start implementing new parts of the idea and here the roles changes again. I get the feeling of completion when I feel happy both about the product and the code behind it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>Goran Gligorin</name><email>goran@gligorin.com</email></author><category term="thoughts" /><summary type="html">I found a very interesting question on Programmers (a Stack Exchange Q&amp;amp;A site):</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Timeboxing - Getting Things Done</title><link href="https://www.gorangligorin.com/blog/timeboxing-getting-things-done" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Timeboxing - Getting Things Done" /><published>2010-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.gorangligorin.com/blog/timeboxing-getting-things-done</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.gorangligorin.com/blog/timeboxing-getting-things-done">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/timeboxing.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Timeboxing&quot; title=&quot;Timeboxing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the 13th of December I’ll have my penultimate exam. It’s nothing I’ll be looking forward to, but it’s necessary evil. The only thing that matters is that I get it done and over with. I want to start living my life and finally start working on my ideas and projects that have been growing in my head for a while now. That and the fact that after 17 years or school I’ll actually get a real and more importantly an official profession are the only two things that keep me going. I know there’s a diploma I’ll have to write after I finish the exams to be able to graduate, but I’ll be treating that as one of my projects, so it should be fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see I have my goal set and the reward for completing it is very compelling. This keeps me somewhat motivated. The problem isn’t the reward though. It’s that it is far away. 2 weeks can be a long time. If you’ve read my post &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/time-is-a-perspective&quot; title=&quot;Time Is a Perspective&quot;&gt;Time is a Perspective&lt;/a&gt; you should understand that 2 weeks with so much things to learn can seem like at least a few months. This is way the ultimate reward of being school free has a very limited motivational value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make studying an easier job I needed to find a way of getting more motivation. I found it while reading a great article my friend suggested - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stevepavlina.com/articles/overcoming-procrastination.htm&quot; title=&quot;Overcoming Procrastination&quot;&gt;Steve Pavlina’s &lt;em&gt;Overcoming Procrastination&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. In section &lt;em&gt;6. Poor Time Management Habits&lt;/em&gt; he suggest an idea he calls &lt;strong&gt;timeboxing&lt;/strong&gt;. You can read more about it in his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stevepavlina.com/blog/2004/10/timeboxing/&quot; title=&quot;Timeboxing&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt;, but the main idea is to take a fixed amount of time and make yourself do something for the duration of it. After you’re done, you reward yourself. For example I made myself write for 30 minutes and then I rewarded myself by watching an episode of House. I’ve tested it with studying and it works quite well. I did come up with a few variations though. They depend on the type of the task you want to do and how much time can you allocate for rewards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;closed-and-open-ended-time-frames&quot;&gt;Closed and open ended time frames&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two types of time frames - closed and open ended. When using the closed ended version you stop doing the task when the time runs out. This is useful when you want to limit your output. I use it when writing the first draft of an article. This helps me focus on the most important parts of content I want to include. For these types of tasks you should use an alarm clock. When it goes off stop what you’re doing and claim your reward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For tasks that you need a push to get going an open time frame is more appropriate. You can use a clock or a stopwatch to know when the time is over. An alarm clock is not suitable for this as you don’t want to get distracted when/if you get the momentum going. The time frame is there for you to know that even if you fail to accomplish anything in it you can enjoy your reward guilt free. This is really suitable for studying. For example I give myself a 45 minute block of time. After a few blocks like this I can study for 60 to 90 minutes before I feel a craving for a break. I then enjoy whatever reward I promised myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;limited-and-unlimited-reward-lengths&quot;&gt;Limited and unlimited reward lengths&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will notice that I didn’t mention what kinds of rewards you can choose. That’s because it doesn’t matter. Anything from taking the rest of the day off, eating something or a TV show will do. The only condition is that you find you reward enjoyable. That will a motivation boost inside of you and you’ll feel less reluctant to take up the task at hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An additional condition can arise when you don’t have a lot of time to get something done. Unlimited length rewards are just not an option in this case. When you have a due date of some kind limited length rewards are the way to go. These types of rewards are essentially closed-ended timeboxed rewards. The best kinds of rewards here are the ones that take up only a limited amount of time by their very nature. Watching an episode of House takes about 45 minutes where as something like browsing the Internet can easily take up a few hours without you even noticing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;progressive-timeboxing&quot;&gt;Progressive Timeboxing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also like to employ a technique I call &lt;strong&gt;progressive timeboxing&lt;/strong&gt;. What I do is I gradually increase the duration of time blocks. This is comes in handy when trying to find the optimal amount of time for timeboxing. I usually start with 30 or 45 minutes add see where it takes me. I usually get up to 60 or even 90 minutes. I depends on the type of task I’m trying to do. Pick a short enough block so you don’t have to shorten it later on, but also don’t make it too short as it won’t bring you much closer to accomplishing your task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timeboxing can be a very effective motivational tool when used correctly. By completing a session you also get a sense of achievement which boosts your motivation even further. I suggest you try it out and see if it suits you. I would of course like to hear what success you’ve reached while employing this technique. And if you came up with your own derivation of it don’t feel hesitant to share :smiley:&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Goran Gligorin</name><email>goran@gligorin.com</email></author><category term="thoughts" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">MvcOpenID - Open Source OpenID Starter Kit for ASP.NET MVC</title><link href="https://www.gorangligorin.com/blog/mvcopenid-open-source-openid-starter-kit-for-asp-net-mvc" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MvcOpenID - Open Source OpenID Starter Kit for ASP.NET MVC" /><published>2010-11-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-11-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.gorangligorin.com/blog/mvcopenid-open-source-openid-starter-kit-for-asp-net-mvc</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.gorangligorin.com/blog/mvcopenid-open-source-openid-starter-kit-for-asp-net-mvc">&lt;p&gt;Last week was quite a productive one for me. Pulling in about 4 to 5 productive hours a day as you can see from the graph below. I’m happy about that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/mvcopenid-productivity.png&quot; title=&quot;Productivity Week 3 November 2010&quot; class=&quot;fancybox&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/mvcopenid-productivity.png&quot; alt=&quot;Productivity Week 3 November 2010&quot; title=&quot;Productivity Week 3 November 2010&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what was I up to, you might ask. Well I’ll tell you. I decided to publish my first open source project. It’s an OpenID Starter Kit for ASP.NET MVC. Essentially it is an ASP.NET MVC empty project with the added functionality that handles users logging-in with their OpenIDs. I’m still at a very early stage, but the core is there. I plan to break the project into 3 parts - Basic, PopUp and AJAX. The difference is essentially in user’s experience when logging-in. Basic and PopUp have a separate page for login. After entering you OpenID the Basic method will redirect you to your OpenID provider’s page while PopUp will open a smaller PopUp window. AJAX approach will have a box popup wherever on the page you are. I’m still unsure how the user gets to OpenID provider’s page with this approach, but I’ll get to that when I get there. Each of these 3 parts will be implemented using Razor and ASPX view engines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I’m not a reinventing-the-wheel kind of a developer my project is using a library called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dotnetopenauth.net&quot; title=&quot;DotNetOpenAuth&quot;&gt;DotNetOpenAuth&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.nerdbank.net/&quot; title=&quot;Andrew Arnott&quot;&gt;Andrew Arnott&lt;/a&gt;. It is a very extensive library for OpenID, OAuth and InfoCard for .NET and I’d be a fool not to use it. The project also uses Entity Framework 4. I’ve also added a guide how to convert the project to get the new features of Entity Framework CTP4 like code-first. But I couldn’t ship that as the CTP license does not permit it. As far as I came to understand from that lawyer talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And speaking of licenses, was that a pain to choose. I spent 3 or 4 days just reading articles, forums and of course licenses themselves. I really liked what Jeff Atwood wrote on the subject in his article &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2007/04/pick-a-license-any-license.html&quot; title=&quot;Jeff Atwood, Pick a License, Any License&quot;&gt;Pick a License, Any License&lt;/a&gt;. Choosing a license is a very crucial step when publishing an open source project. Without it people can’t do much more then look at your code or they’ll violate your copyrights. This is where your chosen license steps in and let’s them know how they can use your code, where are the limitations when publishing their code that uses yours and if/how they need attribute you or the project. When choosing a license I found that the answers to these three questions will leave you standing with just a few choices. That’s a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reading around I was left with Microsoft Public License (Ms-PL), Apache License, version 2.0 and a MIT-style license. I looked what similar projects use. By similar I mean written for the Microsoft’s .Net framework and preferably an ASP.NET MVC related project. It seemed that most of them used Ms-PL so I chose that one, but switched to Apache License v2.0 soon afterward just because it seems to be more widely used so more people will know what’s it about and how to use the source that’s licensed that way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was pretty much it for last week. If you’d like to check out the project itself there’s a few ways to do that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mvcopenid.codeplex.com/&quot; title=&quot;MvcOpenID on CodePlex&quot;&gt;MvcOpenID on CodePlex&lt;/a&gt; - this is the primary hub for the project. Any discussions and issue tracking will take place here. You can download the code or use Mercurial (Hg).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gligoran/mvcopenid&quot; title=&quot;MvcOpenID on GitHub&quot;&gt;MvcOpenID on GitHub&lt;/a&gt; - this is another repository I push the code to. It’s mostly there for git users and also because the GitHub site has a lot of awesome features.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ohloh.net/p/mvcopenid&quot; title=&quot;MvcOpenID on Ohloh&quot;&gt;MvcOpenID on Ohloh&lt;/a&gt; - I’ve also submited MvcOpenID to Ohloh. It’s a free public directory of open source software and people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check the project out and I hope you like it. Any feedback I can get is of course very welcome.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Goran Gligorin</name><email>goran@gligorin.com</email></author><category term="aspnet-mvc" /><category term="openid" /><summary type="html">Last week was quite a productive one for me. Pulling in about 4 to 5 productive hours a day as you can see from the graph below. I’m happy about that.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mercurial (Hg) and Git Global Ignore Files for Windows</title><link href="https://www.gorangligorin.com/blog/mercurial-hg-and-git-global-ignore-files-for-windows" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mercurial (Hg) and Git Global Ignore Files for Windows" /><published>2010-10-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-10-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.gorangligorin.com/blog/mercurial-hg-and-git-global-ignore-files-for-windows</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.gorangligorin.com/blog/mercurial-hg-and-git-global-ignore-files-for-windows">&lt;p&gt;So yet another post that is meant mainly for myself, but maybe someone else will find in it as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ignore pattern I use for Visual Studio projects is the same for both Mercurial and Git:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plain&quot;&gt;build/
*.suo
*.user
_ReSharper*
*.csproj.user
*.resharper.user
*.suo
*.cache
*.trx
Thumbs.db
[Bb]in
[Dd]ebug
[Oo]bj
[Rr]elease
[Tt]est[Rr]esult*
_UpgradeReport_Files
*[Pp]ublish.xml
*.project
*.metadata
logs
*.generated.cs
T4MVC.cs
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only difference is how to set global ignore rules for each of them. I found these two great tutorials for this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mercurial (Hg): &lt;a href=&quot;https://geekswithblogs.net/rob/archive/2010/07/16/mercurial-hg-global-ignore-file-on-windows.aspx&quot;&gt;geekswithblogs.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Git: &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.github.com/git-ignore/&quot;&gt;help.github.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE (16/11/2010): After using Hg for a while with my ASP.NET MVC projects I’ve added a few things to the ignore list.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Goran Gligorin</name><email>goran@gligorin.com</email></author><category term="git" /><category term="mercurial" /><summary type="html">So yet another post that is meant mainly for myself, but maybe someone else will find in it as well.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">TortoiseSVN Global Ignore Pattern</title><link href="https://www.gorangligorin.com/blog/tortoisesvn-global-ignore-pattern" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="TortoiseSVN Global Ignore Pattern" /><published>2010-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.gorangligorin.com/blog/tortoisesvn-global-ignore-pattern</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.gorangligorin.com/blog/tortoisesvn-global-ignore-pattern">&lt;p&gt;I’m mainly posting this for myself, so I don’t lose my SVN’s ignore pattern again. So here it is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plain&quot;&gt;*.o *.lo *.la *.al .libs *.so *.so.[0-9]* *.a *.pyc *.pyo *.rej *~ #*# .#* .*.swp .DS_Store *bin *obj RECYCLER Bin *.user *.suo VSMacros80
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use it for Visual Studio for now. I will update this if I add something along the way.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Goran Gligorin</name><email>goran@gligorin.com</email></author><category term="svn" /><summary type="html">I’m mainly posting this for myself, so I don’t lose my SVN’s ignore pattern again. So here it is:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Atomic Tom - iPhone Band Rocks the Subway</title><link href="https://www.gorangligorin.com/blog/atomic-tom-iphone-band-rocks-the-subway" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Atomic Tom - iPhone Band Rocks the Subway" /><published>2010-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.gorangligorin.com/blog/atomic-tom-iphone-band-rocks-the-subway</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.gorangligorin.com/blog/atomic-tom-iphone-band-rocks-the-subway">&lt;p&gt;This YouTube clip has be sweeping the Internet lately. I’m not usually impressed by music played on mobile phones, but this is something else. This Atomic Tom’s iPhone jam session on the subway is just AMAZING.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;video&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/NAllFWSl998&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was so impressed by this I went to their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.myspace.com/atomictom&quot;&gt;MySpace&lt;/a&gt; page and they’re apparently not a YouTube one hit wonder. There’s a couple of good songs there. I encourage you to give them a hear.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Goran Gligorin</name><email>goran@gligorin.com</email></author><category term="music" /><summary type="html">This YouTube clip has be sweeping the Internet lately. I’m not usually impressed by music played on mobile phones, but this is something else. This Atomic Tom’s iPhone jam session on the subway is just AMAZING.</summary></entry></feed>